let us look at the solution to our full
predication quiz we have this branch
based if-then-else called we're trying
to if convert it using full predication
p1 here is set when r2 is 0 when R 2 is
we branch to the else part so this is
what gets done if r2 is 0 that means
that we do this when p1 is true and then
of course we do this when it's not true
the next part that we want to do is when
should we do the if conversion so what
needs to be the accuracy here let's
first see how many instructions we have
in each of these here we have 3
instructions with the CPI of 0.5 this
always takes us one point five cycles
assuming that there are other things
that can be done in the rest of the
cycle here when this branch is taken we
do two instructions when this branch is
not-taken
we do three instructions so let's split
the difference and say that on average
we do 2.5 instructions at the CPI of 0.5
that means that without a misprediction
we get 1.25 cycles a misprediction adds
10 cycles these two perform equally when
the cost of mispredictions here is 0.25
cycles per branch so pretty much the
difference between these two is 0.25
cycles so on average we can lose this
much to get this to be equal the penalty
for a single misprediction is 10 cycles
if we can lose only 0.25 cycles per
branch that means that only one in 40
branches can be mispredicted one in fort
is 2.5% that means that our correct
prediction needs to be at least 97.5% to
not do the if conversion if the correct
prediction rate is less than this then
we are better off with if conversion